primopdf.com 2017-02-15

# Privacy Policy | Nitro

Revised: 22 June, 2015

Welcome to the website of Nitro Software, Inc. (“Nitro”, “we”, “us” and/or “our”). We have prepared this Privacy Policy to explain how we collect, use, protect and disclose information and data when you use any Nitro website ("Site(s)") and Nitro services, including any software, products or other services offered by Nitro from time to time (collectively, "Services"). "You" refers to you as a user of the Site or Services.

Nitro complies with the U.S. - E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Nitro has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Nitro’s certification, please visit <http://export.gov/safeharbor/>

## Information we collect

### Personal Information:

We collect information that personally identifies you, such as your identity and contact details, including your name, email address, phone number, credit card information, and mailing address (“Personal Information”).

### Product and Service preferences

Normally, we collect your Personal Information from you but on occasion we may obtain information about you from others. We may collect additional information about your company to provide better service for volume orders.

We only collect Personal Information which is necessary for the purposes of your dealings with us. We do not collect information about anyone's political or religious beliefs, ethnic background, criminal history or sexual preferences.

## Purpose of collection & use of Personal Information

The purpose for which we collect Personal Information is to assist us in providing you with the products and services you have requested. Unless otherwise specified in this Privacy Policy, we will not use your Personal Information for any purpose which is not related to the products or services you have requested or for any purpose which you would not reasonably expect us to use the information. We typically use your Personal Information for the following purposes:

### Registration

We request certain Personal Information from you on registration forms and to enable you to create a user name and password when applicable. We use this information to contact you about the Services in which you have expressed interest.

### Orders

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain Personal Information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you.

## Bulletin boards/chat rooms/blogs/forums

Our Site may offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by anyone who has access to them. To request removal of your Personal Information from our blog or community forum, please contact us. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Our blog is also managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access to or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login to the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review the third party’s privacy policy.

## Customer testimonials/comments/reviews

We may post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our Site which may contain Personal Information. We obtain the customer's consent, prior to posting the testimonial, to post the customer’s name along with the customer’s testimonial. If you would like to have us remove any of your comments, please contact us.

## Communications from the site

### Special offers and updates

We may occasionally send you information on products, services, special offers, and promotions. You can sign up for these emails from various pages on our Sites. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out” section below.

### Newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out” section below.

### Product/service-related announcements

We will send you strictly product/service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, to assist you with product usage or notification of product and service maintenance, we might send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature.

### Customer Service

Based upon the Personal Information you provide to us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify information you provided. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the Services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes.

## Choice/Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your Personal Information used for certain purposes when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [unsubscribe@gonitro.com](mailto:unsubscribe@gonitro.com).

## Sharing and disclosure

e will share or sell your Personal Information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy. We do not sell your Personal Information to third parties except as described in this Privacy Policy (see the "Business Transitions" section below).

We may provide your Personal Information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities, such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your Personal Information only as necessary to provide these services to us. We may disclose Personal Information when the disclosure:

  * is required by law; or
  * is necessary to protect our interests or where we believe we have a duty to disclose that information; or
  * has been consented to by you.

## Business Transitions

In the event Nitro goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your Personal Information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or prominent notice on our Site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control that affects your Personal Information.

## Access

You may request that we provide you with access to the Personal Information we hold about you at any time. We will respond to your request for access within 30 days. If your Personal Information changes, or if you no longer desire to use our Services, you may correct, update, delete/remove or deactivate it by making the change in your account or by emailing us or by contacting us by postal mail at the contact information listed below. Generally we will be able to provide you with such access. However, where:

  * the access impacts the privacy of others,
  * the request for access is frivolous or vexatious,
  * there are existing or anticipated legal proceedings,
  * such access can be denied under law or by law enforcement agency, or
  * where the information is evaluative or we have some other reasonable basis not to provide access

We may not be able to provide you with access to such information. If we deny your request for access, we will let you know why. We may also charge a fee to cover our reasonable costs associated with your request.

## Personal information security and data retention

We will take reasonable precautions to protect your Personal Information from loss, misuse or alteration. This includes both physical and technological security measures. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security and you agree that you submit information to us at your own risk. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you Services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your Personal Information to provide you Services, please contact us. However, we will retain and use your Personal Information as necessary to comply with our legal or other obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our rights and agreements.

## Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Nitro and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering our Sites, tracking users’ movements around the Sites and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

Our Sites use various types of cookies and other tracking technologies to collect usage data. These technologies include:

**Per-session cookies** : Used to assess and improve the performance of our Sites for our users. These cookies are anonymous and in no way identify users.

**Persistent cookies** : Used to make areas of our Sites that require a person to be logged in easier to use. For example, we may use persistent cookies in managing support enquiries.

Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our Sites, but your ability to use some features or areas of our Sites may be limited.

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as Flash to store cookie preferences [TEConsent]. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Sites or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as Flash to collect and store information. To manage Flash LSOs, please click here:<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain usage data automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the Site, to track users' movements around the Site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to Personal Information.

At this time, Nitro does not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking, including “do-not-track” signals. You can remove persistent cookies and change your privacy preferences by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” directory. However, certain features of the Site or Services may not work if you delete or disable cookies.

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Sites or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on the Sites and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by contacting [privacy@gonitro.com](mailto:privacy@gonitro.com) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

## Links to other sites

Our Sites contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Nitro. Please be aware that Nitro is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Sites and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by Nitro. Note also that third parties may collect, but we do not authorize them to collect, personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use the Sites or Services.

## Frames

Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our Sites. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to Nitro.

## Single Sign-On

You can log in to our Sites using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

## Social Media Widgets

Our Sites include social media features, such as the Facebook “Like” button and Widgets, the “Share this” button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Sites. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Sites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. Please note the effective date listed at the beginning of the Privacy Policy. By continuing to use the Site or Services, you consent to the revised Privacy Policy.

## Children’s Privacy

We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received Personal Information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete such information from our records.

## Governing Law

Please be aware that your Personal Information and communications may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province, or country. By using our Sites or Services, you agree that the applicable laws in the United States will govern the collection, use, transfer, and disclosure of your Personal Information and communications. The laws in the United States may not be as protective of your privacy as those in your location.
